[ANNE]
Mr. Collins!
[ORLAND]
Daana, please fetch a doctor!
- [DAANA] Yes, sir!
- [KING] Stay calm, Elliott!
[NADIR]
What do we do? He's bleeding!
[VALENTINE] Press some cloth
against the wound!
♪
- [Elliott groans]
- Mister Collins!
Are you awake?
[groans]
[ELLIOTT]
It would seem that I survived.
Bridget, I'm happy you're here
to see me, too!
Am I to assume
that you helped tend to me?
Uh!
[inhales]
Never mind, then.
[ANNE]
Good news!
Seems Mister Collins
is all right!
I wasn't really invested,
either way.
Well, that's rude.
You could at least pretend
like you were worried,
- even if you weren't.
- [CHALLE] You could but not me.
More importantly,
I have a question.
Who did this to you?
Mm?
I haven't a clue.
He was wearing a hood
and it all happened
very suddenly.
Were you robbed?
Oddly, no.
He said he could smell
silver sugar on me
and asked if I was
a silver sugar master.
When I said that I wasn't,
he started slashing away at me.
Do you know something, Challe?
- [gasps]
- You're a warrior fairy?
Why didn't anyone tell me
about that?
[sword swings]
[CHALLE] Did the blade resemble
this one?
Hm. The shimmer on the blade
did look like that
but I don't believe
the metal was silver.
I heard a sound, like a blade
slicing through wind,
and saw a flash of light,
almost red.
[CHALLE]
I see.
There is no question,
the one who assaulted him
was a fairy.
[gasps] You're saying
that someone sent a fairy
to attack Mister Collins?
[CHALLE]
Perhaps so.
That's terrible.
Why would anyone--
[CHALLE]
I don't know.
That's fine.
I survived the ordeal
in one piece,
so the who and why of it
doesn't matter much right now.
You needn't worry about me.
Go.
There's important business
to attend to.
Huh?
The selection is coming soon.
Mister Glen didn't make
the decision to enter lightly.
You owe it to him
to produce a good result.
[distant birds chirp]
[GLEN]
Elliott said that to you?
Yes.
Fortunately, it seems
his injuries aren't too serious.
Hmm, he's truly grown
into a fine young gentleman,
hasn't he?
I trust him
to take good care of Bridget.
I'd be at peace, if only I could
put the matter to rest.
[sighs]
Forgive me.
I'm just speaking my mind,
I know
there's nothing you can do.
[ANNE]
It's all right.
Well, as Elliott said,
you have an important job to do.
Uphold the good reputation
of our shop.
Yes, sir.
We'll make you proud.
♪
Now, shall we begin?
You said
we're making snow, correct?
But snow has no form.
How will we even express it?
It's simple.
I'll draw it for you.
This is snow!
Try making whatever shape
of crystal comes to mind!
[ALL]
Hm.
[ANNE]
These are all lovely
and I think it's good
that there are different sizes.
But since it's snow,
it should be piled up.
A tower might be good!
Oh, yes! I agree!
That's perfect!
We should make it transparent.
It will make for a good effect
if the light in the room
passes through it.
In that case, I think
we should add a bit of color.
That'll be striking
when the light hits it.
We should adjust the kneading.
So, let's increase
the number of folds.
It'll be more glossy.
Mm-hm.
The base will be pure white.
We'll accent it
with the palest blue and pink,
a hint of purple, too.
We'll need to make lots.
And how much is "lots," exactly?
As many as we can, for now.
We're aiming to impress,
so bigger is better, right?
We should have plenty,
if we all work hard.
I have faith in your skills.
So, let's start now!
♪
[crickets chirp]
We're happy?
[all gasp]
No complaints.
Looks good.
[door opens]
I brought him to see!
Hello!
I heard you finished the, uh--
[gasps]
Goodness.
This is amazing.
♪
Ah?
[ORLAND]
Mister Glen!
I can't stay in bed
at a time like this.
I have to see your work.
[running footsteps]
[GLEN]
It's snow.
[exhales]
A snowy landscape.
Lovely, it would be a dream
to see
Saint Lewiston Bell Church
lined with these!
Anne, come here please.
You're the Head of Artisans,
aren't you?
[Anne gasps]
[GLEN] What? You said it
yourself, if I recall.
Ah!
This is wonderful work
you've done.
Anne, go to Lewiston Bell,
to represent
the Paige school's workshop
as our Head of Artisans.
Yes, sir!
Challe, you accompany her.
Whoever it was
that attacked Elliott
may target one of you again.
I've heard rumors that
people are after silver sugar.
Ensure that Anne reaches
the church safely.
Understood?
I will obey your orders.
- [birds chirp]
- [wagon rattles]
[ELLIOTT]
The sun will set before long.
What should we do now,
warrior fairy?
We will continue
to Lewiston just like this.
Visibility should be fine.
It's a full moon.
But we're prepared to camp,
you're sure
we should go all night?
It's to avoid the fairy.
He's attracted by the scent
of silver sugar.
[CHALLE]
So, we need to keep moving.
If we go far enough,
we may be able to elude him.
♪
Now that we've traveled
this far,
perhaps we'll be safe.
[wind howls]
[Anne gasps]
[exhales]
[gasps]
That would be him.
♪
Careful.
[Challe cloths patter]
[CHALLE]
I'll keep him busy.
While I do that, keep moving.
Go, I can catch up with you.
[horse neighs]
♪
[swords clink]
Come back safe!
[grunts]
[MITHRIL]
Don't worry, Anne.
He'll be fine.
You should trust him.
I do.
- [HOODED FAIRY] Obsidian, is it?
- Hm?
I haven't seen a fellow
precious stone in a while.
I don't want to fight you.
I would much rather save you.
Which one among them
holds your wing?
[CHALLE]
You first.
Who and where is your master?
[Hooded Fairy chuckles]
My wings are mine
and mine alone.
[CHALLE]
You're saying you're free, then.
[chuckles]
But being alone
can be rather inconvenient.
I wouldn't mind
having at least one ally.
♪
Allow me to set you free.
I'll chase down your captors
and retrieve your wing
from them.
While I'm at it,
I'll kill them all
and steal that sugar confection.
[CHALLE]
You want sugar confections?
I do and a silver sugar master
as well.
Do they happen to have a master
in their group?
[CHALLE]
Ah. I understand now.
I cannot give you the things
that you desire,
not a one!
[Challe grunts]
This after I said
that I would set you free?
I already have someone
fighting to save me.
So, I have no need of you.
Intriguing.
We're not going fast enough,
Orland, hurry up!
We can't!
The sugar confection will break!
Perhaps, but if that bandit
catches up to us--
That won't happen!
Have faith in Challe's plan.
He won't let that fairy
get one step closer!
[NADIR]
It's Lewiston!
[MARCUS]
Don't rush!
Unload it carefully.
[ELLIOTT]
We've just arrived!
We're from the main Paige
workshop!
I'm here on behalf
of Glen Paige.
My name is Elliott Collins.
We have brought
a sugar confection.
We're entering the selection.
[BROOK] Well, well.
Please come this way.
Bring your sugar confection--
- What is the meaning of this?
- [ELLIOTT] Good,
- let's get started!
- He said
they wouldn't be participating!
♪
[BROOK] It is time to begin
this year's selection process.
The participants are:
the main workshop
of the Radcliffe school,
of the Mercury school,
and the main workshop
of the Paige school.
Hm?
[BROOK]
First, the Radcliffe Workshop.
Go ahead.
Ah.
Hm.
[priests impressed]
- [PRIEST 1] Oh, splendid.
- [PRIEST 2] Very impressive
[ANNE] It looks like Challe.
It must be Keith's work.
[MARCUS]
Our theme is the founding king,
whose various depictions
and achievements
will be represented.
This piece is
but one such example.
We envision a number of them
standing in rows in the church.
- [PRIEST 3] I see.
- [PRIEST 4] How ambitious.
[BROOK]
Next, the Mercury Workshop.
If you would.
[JOHN]
We will create 12 spheres,
each with one of
the Twelve Patron Saints within,
as you see here.
The pieces would line the church
on each side.
[BROOK]
And finally, the Paige Workshop.
Go ahead.
[exhales]
Huh?
Hm.
The theme of our confection
is snow.
[indistinct chatter]
[ANNE] It's completely different
from how it looked
in the workshop, but why?
[BROOK] Is something wrong?
Please continue.
[ANNE]
These are snow crystals.
The way it cleanses the soul
represents Holy Beginnings.
[grunts]
[ANNE] When visitors come
to the church,
our piece will...
This is terrible.
[ANNE]
Everything's wrong.
What should I do?
[door opens]
♪
[gasps]
[ANNE]
Challe.
Light!
Oh!
One moment, Father.
Could we cast some light
on our piece?
I want you to see it
as it would look
in the Holy Beginnings Festival!
♪
[all laughing]
[giggles]
That's quite a change!
[dazzling sound]
[ANNE] Once again, the theme
of our piece is "snow."
Snow falls from heaven,
with a prayer that good fortune
will come in the new year.
It shrouds the kingdom
in pure white.
We gave form
to those shining crystals,
which make everything new,
and chose to depict a snowscape.
This would be one of many.
We hope to line the church
with them.
[ANNE]
That's all.
[BROOK]
Any of these sugar confections
would be worthy of
- the Holy Beginnings Festival?
- The whole matter was settled.
Let's give the fathers a moment
- to deliberate.
- This is unique.
It seems that we've already come
to our decision.
It is quite clear
that the workshop best suited
for this
Holy Beginnings Festival
- is the Paige School...
- [gasps]
...and their beautiful
snowscape confection!
[chuckles]
[HEAD PRIEST 1] Artisans
of the Paige school workshop,
we will entrust you
with the full display,
to make this church truly shine.
Please do your best
until the end of the year,
so we can share your vision
of hope and rebirth
with the entire kingdom!
[ELLIOTT]
Understood!
[ANNE]
I can't believe it.
We did it!
They chose us!
That went so well, I wish
I could have made this with you!
- Oh, right!
- Huh?
Anne, hold out your hand, please.
Hm?
What? You're sure? But why?
It's only fair.
When Mister Glen said
he'd throw you out
if we weren't chosen,
you should have countered
with a demand of your own,
instead of just saying yes!
If you'd been thinking
on your toes,
you would have asked
for the wing back
if we won the selection today.
She's not that clever!
Stop expecting the impossible
from poor Anne!
- [grunts]
- [chuckles]
Frankly, we were feeling a bit
sorry for you... [chuckles]
...so we made a decision.
If our workshop
was chosen today,
we'd pay you in kind.
I knew it right from the start,
you're just
like the first silver sugar.
[exhales]
You know, I keep hearing that,
but no one will explain it
to me.
What does
"the first silver sugar" mean?
It means
"that which brings change."
When you refine silver sugar,
you leave sugar apples
in cold water overnight, right?
And you always have to add
a handful of silver sugar.
In our school, that's called
"the first silver sugar."
Without it, no matter how long
you soak the sugar apples,
their bitterness
will never go away.
That's why the first
silver sugar is special.
It brings change.
It starts something new.
I had high hopes for you
and so I called you
that endearingly.
Luckily, you met
all my expectations!
Thank you, Anne.
You've taught our school
how to take
a fresh step forward.
So, I won't tie you down
any longer.
You're free to do
as you please now.
[gasps]
[ANNE]
Challe? [echoing]
[CHALLE] I smell the aroma
of silver sugar.
That sweet, beloved scent.
Like it's reaching out
to embrace me.
Ah, you're awake.
Huh?
[MITHRIL]
Is that a cut on your arm I see?
[gasps]
Hm.
[ANNE]
That looks bad.
Are you all right?
[CHALLE]
Yes.
I'll heal soon.
I see.
And what about the fairy?
He ran away but next time,
he'll be dead.
[exhales]
As long as you're safe,
that's all that matters.
Thank you again, Challe.
You're always working hard
to protect me.
[CHALLE]
What's that?
Oh, they're returning your wing.
Since they were chosen
in the selection today,
they said I've done enough.
I don't have to work for them
anymore if I don't want
but then...
Mm?
♪
[ANNE] The real work
for the Holy Beginnings Festival
starts now.
Is it really all right for me
to leave them alone?
Say, I was wondering,
if maybe I should stay
at the Paige Workshop
until the festival is over,
at least.
[MITHRIL]
Oh?
It's only fair.
I haven't fulfilled
my responsibilities.
I haven't truly rebuilt
the workshop yet.
So for now,
until this project is complete,
I want to give them my best.
Is that all right?
[giggles]
That sounds just lovely to me!
The bed there is
awfully comfortable, you know?
You can do whatever it is
you please.
As long as we're together,
I'm content.
Thank you both.
Good, then!
I'll go tell them the news
right away!
I'm sure everyone was secretly
hoping they could keep you!
That's a relief
and I'm glad you're happy, too!
I'm sorry about this.
I'm just dragging you along.
[CHALLE]
It doesn't bother me.
You're still interesting
to watch.
Everything else is just a bore.
[Anne chuckles]
I'm sorry
this has taken so long.
Thank you for waiting on me
to return your wing.
This is yours alone, take it.
[chuckles softly]
Huh?
You saved me.
It's done.
You became a silver sugar master
by your own strength.
Hold your head up high.
You've earned it.
I will.
♪
[CHALLE] To you, who have become
a silver sugar master,
I wish many blessings.
♪